<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog.</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>blog.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
      
        <managingEditor>gabrielzschmitz@protonmail.com
          
            (gabrielzschmitz)
          
        </managingEditor>
      

      
    

    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>gabrielzschmitz@protonmail.com (gabrielzschmitz)</author>
      <guid>/blog/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;about&#34; &gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#about&#34;&gt;
        #
    &lt;/a&gt;
    About
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my personal blog!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m Gabriel dos Santos Schmitz, a passionate software developer, researcher, and
tech enthusiast. In this space, I share my journey through various projects,
challenges, and the latest insights I gather along the way. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s coding
tutorials, new technologies, or the latest trends in software development, this
blog serves as a space to document what I’m learning and experimenting with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-to-expect&#34; &gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-to-expect&#34;&gt;
        ##
    &lt;/a&gt;
    What to Expect
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coding challenges&lt;/strong&gt;: I love solving problems in multiple programming
languages and sharing my solutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Projects&lt;/strong&gt;: I often work on open-source projects and document their progress
here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tech talks&lt;/strong&gt;: Insights into emerging technologies, methodologies, and tools
I find interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research&lt;/strong&gt;: A deeper dive into some of the academic and practical aspects of
software and systems design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to browse through my posts, and don’t hesitate to reach out if you
have any questions or suggestions. I&amp;rsquo;m always open to new ideas and
collaboration!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Journey into Software Development</title>
      <link>/blog/posts/first/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>gabrielzschmitz@protonmail.com (gabrielzschmitz)</author>
      <guid>/blog/posts/first/first/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello and welcome to my first blog post!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I begin this blogging adventure, I thought it would be fitting to share a
little about my journey into software development. I’ve always been intrigued by
how things work—whether it’s computers, devices, or systems. But it wasn’t until
my teenage years that I truly discovered my passion for coding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-beginning&#34; &gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-beginning&#34;&gt;
        #
    &lt;/a&gt;
    The Beginning
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many developers, my journey started with Minecraft mods in &lt;code&gt;Java&lt;/code&gt; (Yuck!).
What began as a hobby quickly grew into a deeper passion for programming. Over
time, I ventured into low-level programming with &lt;code&gt;C&lt;/code&gt; and began tinkering with
simple &lt;code&gt;NCurses&lt;/code&gt; applications. These early experiences sparked my curiosity and
set me on a path of exploring more complex and challenging areas of software
development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-projects&#34; &gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#building-projects&#34;&gt;
        #
    &lt;/a&gt;
    Building Projects
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the key things that has kept me motivated throughout my development
journey is working on real-world projects. Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve contributed to
open-source projects, created my own tools, and tackled coding challenges. It’s
been a rewarding experience seeing my work come to life and be used by others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, I’ve spent a lot of time focusing on algorithms, data structures,
and systems design. These areas have taught me how to think critically and
optimize solutions for complex problems. I’ve also recently been diving into the
world of &lt;code&gt;Golang&lt;/code&gt; to tackle a variety of software challenges, including my most
recent research in post quantum cryptography at blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-ahead&#34; &gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#looking-ahead&#34;&gt;
        #
    &lt;/a&gt;
    Looking Ahead
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I continue this journey, I’m excited to share what I’m learning here on my
blog. I’ll be posting about projects I’m working on and maybe somethings about
my research or related topics. My hope is that you’ll find some useful insights
here and maybe even learn something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, and I look forward to sharing more with you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- &lt;em&gt;gabrielzschmitz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
